<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scala on Software Engineering Blog</title>
    <link>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/tags/scala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scala on Software Engineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 20:47:51 +0430</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mostafa-asg.github.io/tags/scala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study - Solve Crosswords Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/solve-hackerrank-crosswords-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 20:47:51 +0430</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/solve-hackerrank-crosswords-101/</guid>
      <description>As a software engineer, I always enjoy solving problems and that&amp;rsquo;s why I sometimes go to the coding challenge websites like hackerrank and pick one problem to solve. This time I searched in functional programming category and crosswords-101 caught my eye and I decided to solve it in Scala in a very clean and understandable way and not in a contest style way of programming!
This article is going to reveal how I solved this puzzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slick Actions Composition</title>
      <link>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/slick-actions-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 11:28:54 +0430</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/slick-actions-composition/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to insert a new row to a table which has auto increment primary key; Also some additional information must be persist in other tables. At the end you also want to return the inserted generated ID. Imaging you are developing a new web application, and you are working on user registration code. Each time a new user signs up, you want to store his credential in users table and all of his roles in userRoles table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Readable Code in Scala</title>
      <link>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/more-readable-code-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 16:33:30 +0430</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/more-readable-code-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>As a Java developer, I &amp;rsquo;ve always had argument with my colleagues to use Scala instead Java. They complained that Scala is a complex language and Java is a more readable and simple one so I never had the opportunity to use Scala well. Fortunately, recently I &amp;rsquo;ve just joined to the startup company called snapptrip.com, and we use Scala for all the backend services. A few days ago, I was working on a peace of code in Scala to register a new user into the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Internal DSL in Scala</title>
      <link>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/writing-internal-dsl-in-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 18:13:50 +0430</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mostafa-asg.github.io/post/writing-internal-dsl-in-scala/</guid>
      <description>Definition of DSL A DSL is a computer language, specialized for a specific domain. A DSL is essentially the opposite of a general programming languages(GPL), I mean every language that can be used to develop something. For example, Java, C#, and Scala are all GPL languages. With a DSL, we want only to solve a specific domain problem, so we design the language specifically for the domain. A DSL can’t be used outside of the domain, because it is not designed for flexibility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>